A Guide to the Adèle Goodman Clark papers, 1849-1978
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Series XIII: Religious Materials, undated, 1893-1970
  - Subseries D: Topical File, undated, 1893-1970
    - Sister Mary Rosa Correspondence, 1927 (Box 166)
    - Stories About the Catholic Church [Nora Houston], undated (Box 166)
    - Sunday School Questionnaire, undated (Box 166)
    - Sunday School Training Manual [Edith Clark Cowles], 1916 (Box 166)
- Series XIV: Art, undated, 1850-1971
  - Subseries A: Art Club of Richmond, undated, 1895-1919
    - Academy Committee--Memoranda, Minutes, Notes, Reports #1 (Box 167)
    - Academy Committee--Memoranda, Minutes, Notes, Reports #2 (Box 167)
    - Academy/Liberty--Loan Garden Fete Committee, 1917 (Box 167)
    - American Federation of the Arts, Bulletins, Memoranda, Reports, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 167)
    - Board of Directors/President--Memoranda, Minutes, undated, 1917 (Box 167)
    - Circulars, undated (Box 167)
    - Constitution/By-laws, 1904 (Box 167)
    - Correspondence (Box 167)
      - Drafts and Notes [Nora Houston] (1 of 2), undated (Box 167)
    - Correspondence (Box 168)
      - Drafts and Notes [Nora Houston] (2 of 2), undated (Box 168)
      - General, 1910-1919 (Box 168)
    - Endowment Committee--Correspondence, Memoranda, Notes and Reports, 1910-1911 (Box 168)
    - Exhibit Data, undated (Box 168)
    - Financial History/Memoranda/Statements, 1895-1917 (Box 168)
    - Handbills, undated (Box 168)
    - Invitations, undated (Box 168)
    - Liberty Bonds Subscription Cards, undated (Box 168)
    - Membership Committee Report, 1916 (Box 168)
    - Membership Lists, undated (Box 168)
    - Membership Lists, Notes (Box 168)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1914 (Box 169)
    - Notes/Organizational Data (1 of 2), undated (Box 169)
    - Notes/Organizational Data (2 of 2), undated (Box 169)
    - Officer List, 1914-1916 (Box 169)
    - Pamphlet, 1914 (Box 169)
    - Resolutions, undated (Box 169)
    - Salary Agreements [Nora Houston], 1910-1915 (Box 169)
    - School Prospectuses, 1911-1915 (Box 169)
    - Sketchbook--Lucy R. Mason, undated (Box 169)
    - Sketchbooks--Elizabeth Wood Morris, 1911 (Box 169)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1914 (Box 169)
    - Virginia Painters/Sculptors List (Box 169)
    - "Year in Richmond" Calendar account, Correspondence, Memoranda, Notes, 1912-1913 (Box 169)
  - Subseries B: Atelier, undated, 1918-1937
    [merged with the restored Academy in the spring of 1930]
    - Art Data/Lists, undated (Box 169)
    - Budgetary Material, 1918-1922 (Box 169)
    - Correspondence (Box 170)
      - Art Studio Construction, 1928-1930 (Box 170)
      - General, 1918-1937 (Box 170)
      - Handicrafts and Occupational Therapy, 1918-1920 (Box 170)
      - Japan Paper Company, 1929, 1931 (Box 170)
      - Ruffin and Sloan, 1918-1924 (Box 170)
    - Filing Data/Memos (Box 170)
    - Japan Paper Company--Sample Material (Box 170)
    - Leaflets, undated, 1921-1922 (Box 170)
    - "Plea for Art"--paper by Theresa Pollak, 192? (Box 171)
    - Ruffin and Sloan--Lease Agreements, 1924 (Box 171)
    - Student Data, undated, 1919-1921 (Box 171)
    - Study Scholarships Memoranda, 1919-1920 (Box 171)
  - Subseries C: Virginia League of Fine Arts and Handicrafts, undated, 1919-1934
    [grew out of the Atelier and later merged with the Academy]
    - American Federation of Arts--Brochures,Programs,Reports and Surveys, undated, 1925 (Box 171)
    - Art Extension Lists, 1927-1931 (Box 171)
    - Awards, undated (Box 171)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 171)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1919-1931 (Box 171)
    - Exhibit Cards, undated (Box 171)
    - Exhibition Committee, undated (Box 171)
    - Fire Insurance Policy, 1934 (Box 171)
    - Incorporation Certificate, undated (Box 171)
    - Membership Lists, undated (Box 172)
    - Memoranda, undated, 1920 (Box 172)
    - Minutes, 1924-1925 (Box 172)
    - Newspaper Clippings [photocopied], undated (Box 172)
    - Notes, undated (Box 172)
    - Virginia Artists List, undated (Box 172)
    - Virginia, University of--Art Extension Course Material, 1920-1921 (Box 172)
  - Subseries D: Richmond Academy of Arts/Academy of Sciences and Fine Arts, undated, 1917-1953
    - Academy Fund, undated (Box 172)
    - Academy News, 1932-1933 (Box 172)
    - Annual reports, 1936-1938 (Box 172)
    - Artists Guild of the Academy, undated (Box 172)
    - Beaux Arts Ball, April 27, 1932 (Box 172)
    - Board of Trustees (Box 172)
      - Agendas, 1940-1941 (Box 172)
      - Memoranda, 1930-1940 (Box 172)
      - Minutes, 1931, 1936-1941 (Box 172)
      - Reports, 1936 (Box 172)
    - Bulletins, undated (Box 172)
    - By-Laws and Charter, 1932 (Box 172)
    - Circulars, undated, 1931-1941 (Box 172)
    - Class Registers, undated, 1952-1953 (Box 172)
    - Correspondence (Box 172)
      - General, 1917-1923, 1930-1934 (Box 172)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1935-1946, 1949-1950 (Box 173)
      - Virginia Survey Staff, 1934 (Box 173)
    - Essay--"Art in the South Before the War" [author unknown] (Box 173)
    - Exhibition Material (1 of 2), undated (Box 173)
    - Exhibition Material (2 of 2), undated (Box 173)
    - Incorporation Certificate, undated (Box 173)
    - Instructor's Class Cards, 1931 (Box 173)
    - Membership Applications, 1930 (Box 173)
    - Membership/Patron Lists, undated (Box 173)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1930-1932 (Box 174)
    - Notebook [Adèle Clark], undated (Box 174)
    - Notes/Outlines, undated (Box 174)
    - Officer Lists, undated,1937 (Box 174)
    - Organizational History, undated (Box 174)
    - Organization Committee--Minutes, 1931 (Box 174)
    - Outline of Aims and Program, undated (Box 174)
    - Plat, undated (Box 174)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 174)
    - Southern States Art League--Bulletins, 1925-1940 (Box 174)
    - Southern States Art League--Convention/Exhibition Material, 1921-1942 (Box 174)
    - Statement of Accounts, 1940-1941 (Box 174)
    - Survey of Virginia's Artistic Wealth, undated (Box 174)
    - Tournament of Arts and Crafts, 1931-1932 (Box 174)
    - Virginia Art Index Patron List (Box 175)
  - Subseries E: Virginia Arts Commission [established 1916], undated, 1913-1965
    - Agendas, 1949-1964 (Box 175)
    - Art Appraisal List, undated (Box 175)
    - Committee to Establish Arts Commission, 1913-1916, 1922 (Box 175)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1940-1965 (Box 175)
    - Flag Data, 1954 (Box 175)
    - Invitations, undated, 1949, 1952 (Box 175)
    - Laws Relating to the Art Commission, 1938 (Box 176)
    - Memoranda, undated, 1941-1963 (Box 176)
    - Minutes, 1940-1952 (Box 176)
    - Minutes, 1953-1964 (Box 177)
    - Newspaper Clippings, undated, 1962 (Box 177)
    - Notes, undated (Box 177)
    - "Notes on Art Commission of the Commonwealth of Virginia" [Adèle Clark], undated (Box 177)
    - Oath Certificates, 1965 (Box 177)
    - Radio Broadcast Script, 1951 (Box 177)
    - Reports, undated (Box 177)
    - Rules and Procedures of the Art Commission, 1950 (Box 177)
    - State Capital Improvements Data, 1955 (Box 177)
    - Virginia Declaration of Rights, undated (Box 177)
    - Virginia State Police Memorial Gallery Dedication, 1947 (Box 177)
    - Virginia World War II Memorial Commission, 1953 (Box 177)
  - Subseries F: Works Project Administration/Virginia Arts Project, undated, 1935-1942
    - Allocation Receipts and Requests, 1940-1942 (Box 177)
    - Antiques Data/Inventory, 1938-1939 (Box 177)
    - Artists/Paintings Lists, undated, 1940 (Box 177)
    - Art Production Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 178)
    - Art Submissions [includes photos and sketches], 1939-1940 (Box 178)
    - Biographical Statement--Adèle Clark, undated (Box 178)
    - Bi-Weekly Work Reports, 1942 (Box 178)
    - "Brief Survey of Modern Painting" [by Alfred H. Barr, Jr.] (Box 178)
    - Captions, undated, 1941 (Box 178)
    - Correspondence (Box 178)
      - General, undated, 1935-1942 (Box 178)
      - Glasgold, C.A, 1936-1940 (Box 178)
      - Houston, Nora, 1939 (Box 178)
      - Slemp, C. Bascom, 1940-1942 (Box 178)
    - Employee Data, undated, 1940 (Box 179)
    - Employment Statements and Summaries, 1940 (Box 179)
    - Fairfax Federal Art Gallery--Memoranda, 1939 (Box 179)
    - Fairfax Federal Art Gallery: Report of Exhibitions Received and Sent Shipping Receipts (Box 179)
    - Federal Art Gallery Show Announcements, undated (Box 179)
    - Federal Art Project Calender, 1939 (Box 179)
    - Federal Works Agency--Section of Fine Arts Bulletins, 1941 (Box 179)
    - Graphic Production/Job Orders, 1940-1942 (Box 179)
    - Index of American Design (Box 179)
      - Exhibition Material, undated, 1940 (Box 179)
      - Instructional Data, undated (Box 179)
      - Inventory Data, undated, 1936-1941 (Box 179)
      - Inventory Instructions, 1942 (Box 179)
    - Inter-office Memoranda, undated, 1936-1942 (Box 179)
    - Job Analyses, undated (Box 180)
    - Lynchburg Art Gallery Exhibition Notices, undated, 1939-1940 (Box 180)
    - Materials Lists, 1941 (Box 180)
    - Miscellaneous Reports and Statistical Data, 1939-1941 (Box 180)
    - Monthly Progress Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 180)
    - Monthly Progress Reports (Box 180)
      - Big Stone Gap Art Gallery, 1940, 1942 (Box 180)
      - Fairfax, February - June 1939 (Box 180)
      - King William, 1940-1941 (Box 180)
      - Lynchburg, 1942 (Box 180)
    - Narrative Reports (Box 180)
      - Academy of Sciences and Fine Arts, 1937 (Box 180)
      - Big Stone Gap Demonstration Gallery October, 1936 (Box 180)
      - Middlesex County Museum, 1937-1942 (Box 180)
      - Petersburg, 1937 (Box 181)
    - Newspaper Clippings, undated, 1942 (Box 181)
    - Notes, undated (Box 181)
    - "Notes on the Index of American Design in Virginia" [Adèle Clark], undated (Box 181)
    - Personnel Application [Adèle Clark], 1936 (Box 181)
    - Questionnaire, undated (Box 181)
    - Reports of Work Completed (Box 181)
      - April 1941 - June 1941 (Box 181)
      - July 1941 - October 1941 (Box 181)
      - December 1941 - February 1942 (Box 181)
    - Resolutions, 1936, 1940 (Box 181)
    - Ship Figurehead Descriptions, undated, 1938 (Box 181)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1937-1941 (Box 181)
    - State Property Inventory Project, 1941 (Box 181)
    - Stationery Samples, undated (Box 181)
    - Transaction for Allocations of Paintings to Public Institutions--Memoranda, 1940 (Box 181)
    - Travel Vouchers, 1941 (Box 181)
    - Unit Requisitions, 1940-1941 (Box 181)
    - Virginia Artists Lists, 1940-1941 (Box 181)
    - Virginia Music Project--"Virginia Variations," 1941 (Box 182)
    - Working Procedures (Box 182)
    - WPA "Capture and Record"--Study Progress Report, December 19, 1936 (Box 182)
    - "WPA Record in Virginia," October 1936 (Box 182)
  - Subseries G: Other Art Organizations, undated, 1932-1971
    - Archives of American Art, 1965-1966 (Box 182)
    - Art Center Club, undated (Box 182)
    - Art Publication Society, 1938, 1945 (Box 182)
    - Camp Lee [12th Quartermaster Training Regiment], 1942, 1947 (Box 182)
    - Community Recreation Association--Fun with Hobbies, 1943 (Box 182)
    - Crafts Carnival Committee, 1951 (Box 182)
    - Federated Arts of Richmond, Inc., undated (Box 182)
    - Linden Gallery, 1951 (Box 182)
    - Richmond Artists Association [bulletins,exhibits,notices, memoranda], 1956-1971 (Box 182)
    - Richmond Professional Institute--Fine Art Department, 1952, 1955 (Box 182)
    - Richmond Symphony Orchestra, 1932 (Box 182)
    - Virginia Allied Artists Group, undated, 1943-1945 (Box 182)
    - Virginia Art Alliance, 1929-1956 (Box 182)
    - Virginia Crafts Association, 1947-1948 (Box 182)
    - Virginia Education Association--Art Section, undated, 1948 (Box 182)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1936-1937 (Box 182)
  - Subseries H: Printed Materials, undated, 1901-1969
    - Art and Art Books--Advertisements and Catalogs (1 of 2), undated (Box 183)
    - Art and Art Books--Advertisements and Catalogs (2 of 2), undated (Box 183)
    - Art Museum Bulletins (Box 183)
      - Valentine Museum, undated (Box 183)
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, undated (Box 183)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 183)
    - Art Museum Catalog (Box 183)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, undated (Box 183)
    - Art Periodicals (Box 183)
      - American Artist, April 1953 (Box 183)
      - American Art Student, September 1924 (Box 183)
      - Art Periodicals (Box 184)
      - American Magazine of Art, 1920, 1925 (Box 184)
      - "Art and Archaeology" Archaeological Institute of American Publishers (Box 184)
      - Art Digest, November 1926, February 1930 (Box 184)
      - Arts in Virginia, 1964,1965 (Box 184)
      - Atelier, April 1931 (Box 184)
      - Four Arts, September 1934 (Box 184)
      - International Studio, 1934 (Box 184)
      - Journal of the Archives of American Art, 1965-1966 (Box 184)
      - Mentor, 1913 (Box 184)
    - Art School Publications, undated, 1925-1929 (Box 184)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Bulletins (Box 185)
      - American Art Galleries, undated (Box 185)
      - Anderson Gallery, undated, 1936 (Box 185)
      - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1928-1935 (Box 185)
      - Valentine Museum, 1957-1966 (Box 185)
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1947-1969 (Box 185)
      - Miscellaneous (1 of 4), undated 1931-1954 (Box 185)
      - Miscellaneous (2 of 4), undated 1933-1956 (Box 185)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Bulletins (Box 186)
      - Miscellaneous (3 of 4), undated, 1901-1933 (Box 186)
      - Miscellaneous (4 of 4), undated, 1924 (Box 186)
    - Exhibition Catalogs (1 of 2), 1911, 1916, 1920 (Box 186)
    - Exhibition Catalogs (2 of 2), undated, 1911, 1917, 1935 (Box 186)
    - Literary Announcements, Brochures and Bulletins, undated, 1925-1938 (Box 186)
    - Music Literature, undated, 1938 (Box 187)
  - Subseries I: Topical File, undated, 1917-1968
    - Art Classes Receipts, 1950 (Box 187)
    - Art Instructor Service Reports--City of Richmond, 1954-1955 (Box 187)
    - Biographical Sketch--Robert Gills [Adèle Clark], undated (Box 187)
    - Carillon Art Exhibit Lists and Memoranda, 1955-1957 (Box 187)
    - Correspondence (Box 187)
      - Art Museum School, 1943-1966 (Box 187)
      - Art Supply, 1948-1959 (Box 187)
      - Church Art Classes, 1938-1951 (Box 187)
    - Color Data, undated (Box 187)
    - Commercial Standards for Artists' Oil Paints, 1940 (Box 187)
    - Contest Brochure and Memoranda, 1948 (Box 187)
    - Data Sheets, Who's Who in American Art, 1924-1937 (Box 187)
    - Drama Project, undated (Box 187)
    - Essay (Box 187)
      - Clark, Adèle "Art in Richmond: Decorated Furniture, What Miss Pleasants has accomplished," undated (Box 187)
      - Clark, Adèle "Seeing A Picture with Open Eyes--What a Picture May Mean to You," undated (Box 187)
      - Unknown author "Arts in Nature," undated (Box 187)
    - Exhibit Entries and Notices--Adèle Clark/Nora Houston, undated, 1930-1931 (Box 187)
    - Interview--Adèle Clark, November 16,1963 (Box 187)
    - Ions, Estelle de Willoughby--Memoranda, undated (Box 187)
    - Lithograph Stones--Correspondence and Lists, 1960 (Box 187)
    - Loom Advertisements and Notes, undated (Box 187)
    - "Memoranda Regarding Furniture Shown in Accompanying Photographs" [E.S. Goodman] (Box 187)
    - Music Class Notes [Adeline Cox?], undated, 1934 (Box 187)
    - Notebooks--Art, undated (Box 188)
    - Notes (Box 188)
      - undated (Box 188)
      - "American Mural Painting," undated (Box 188)
      - Painting Techniques [Nora Houston], undated (Box 188)
      - Roman Art, undated (Box 188)
      - Sculpture, undated (Box 188)
    - "Notes on Early History of Art in Richmond, Virginia," by Adèle Clark, 1968 (Box 188)
    - "Notes on Recreational Art" by J.Peter Reynolds, 1957 (Box 188)
    - Painting Lists, undated (Box 188)
    - Paper--"William and Mary News," undated (Box 188)
    - Poetry, undated (Box 188)
    - Portrait Memoranda, 1951 (Box 188)
    - Registration Cards--Department of Recreation and Parks, Richmond, 1949-1957 (Box 188)
    - Slemp [C. Bascom] Bust Memoranda, 1978 (Box 188)
    - Soap Sculpture Material, undated (Box 188)
    - Theater Programs, undated, 1948 (Box 188)
    - American Architect and Building News (Box 189)
    - Cashbook--Accounts of Atelier of Nora and Adèle Clark, November 1917 - October 1922 (Box 189)
    - "Das Museum" (Box 189)
    - "Picturesque Europe" parts 22 and 27 (Box 189)
    - "Picturesque Europe" parts 28 and 41 (Box 189)
    - Virginia Statewide Recreation Bulletins, 1938-1941 (Box 189)
  - Subseries J: Artwork, undated, 1850-1939
    - Drawings/Sketches--Mary Crump Bouldin, undated (Box 190)
    - Drawings/Lithographs/Sketches/Sketchbooks--Adèle Clark, [5 folders] undated, 1898-1899 (Box 190)
    - Lithograph--William Polk Delton, 1929(?) (Box 190)
    - Art Designs & Patterns--Gertrude Clark Dew(?), undated (Box 190)
    - Drawings/Lithographs/Sketches--Nora Houston, undated (Box 190)
    - Drawings/Sketches--Miscellaneous and Unidentified Artists, undated (Box 190)
    - Art Reproductions and Illustrations, [5 folders], undated, 1850(?), 1935 (Box 191)
    - Drawings and Lithograph--"Richmond Market at Christmas" [Adèle Clark], undated (Box 192)
    - Artwork of Children,[8 folders], undated, 1939 (Box 192)
    - Sketches of Governor's Mansion [Nora Houston], undated (Box 193)
    - Chalk sketch--"History of Transportation" [artist unknown], undated (Box 194)
    - Watercolor Painting--"Story of Shelter" [artist unknown], undated (Box 194)
    - Lithographs/Sketches [artists unknown], undated (Box 194)
    - Art Illustrations and Reproductions--(includes 2 bound volumes) [FRAGILE], undated (Box 195)
    - Needlepoint Designs, undated (Box 195)
    - Art Illustrations and Reproductions [FRAGILE], undated (Box 196)
    - Prints--Virginia Residences, 1929-1930 (Box 196)
    - [Collection of Bookplates by artist Julius J. Lankes. The bookplates are framed and numbered 1 through 58.] (Box 197)
    - Framed bookplates numbers 1 through 29. (Box 197)
    - Framed bookplates numbers 20 through 58. (Box 198)
    - Approximately 35 copper engravings (on wood blocks) of people, rooms, calling cards and other items, including the word VOTE. Most are 3 by 4 inches. (Box 199)
    - Unidentified Address & Ledger Books [1 folder & 3 bound volumes], undated (Box 200)
    - Unidentified Ledger Books [2 bound volumes], undated (Box 201)
- Series XV: Ephemera and Photographs, 1850s - 1970s
  - Subseries A: Newspaper Clippings, 1910s-1970s
    - Art, suffrage, voting, 1910s-1930s (Box 202)
    - Editorials on Suffrage, Lila Meade Valentine clippings, 1916-1917, Valentine Memorial clippings, 1926, Clippings form Lila Meade Valentine's desk, Suffrage, Greatest Virginian Contest, 1920s (Box 203)
    - League of Women Voters 1920s-1930s, Valentine Memorial Dedication, New York 1909, Art College for Women, Mapp-Byrd Governor's Campaign 1920s, Hoover-Roosevelt Campaign 1932, Suffrage 1910s, Suffrage Movement in England (Box 204)
    - Local and state issues, 1910s-1920s (Box 205)
    - National League of Women's Voters, 1920s (Box 206)
    - Scrapbook with clippings labeled "History of Virginia League of Women Voters" 1920s, second scrapbook of clippings on suffrage, 1910s (Box 207)
    - Scrapbook of clippings labeled "League of Women Voters History 1921-1925"; Many clippings on Lady Astor (Box 208)
    - Scrapbooks (two) of clippings on suffrage, 1910s (Box 209)
    - State, national politics and suffrage, 1910s (Box 210)
    - State, national politics and suffrage, 1910s (Box 211)
    - State, national politics, suffrage convention material, 1910s-1920s (Box 212)
    - State, national politics, 1920s-1930s (Box 213)
    - State, national and international politics, League of Nations, World Court, 1920s (Box 214)
    - State, national politics, 1920s, League of Women Voters, 1920s, World Court and peace issues, 1920s (Box 215)
    - State and national politics, other issues, 1920s-1940s (Box 216)
    - State, national politics and suffrage, 1920s-1930s (Box 217)
    - State, national politics and suffrage, 1920s (Box 218)
    - State, national politics and suffrage 1920s-1930s, biographical data regarding members of the League of Women Voters 1920s, art related clippings 1918 and 1928, government and social legislation 1920s, League of Women Voters 1936, League of Woman Voters Convention 1932, Labor related, women hours and pay 1936, folder on Adèle Clark (Box 219)
    - State, national politics, suffrage, voting 1920s-1930s, clippings pertaining to Adèle Clark (Box 220)
    - State, national politics, race issues, women organizations, primary reform, taxation, League of Women Voters Second Vice-President, 1920s (Box 221)
    - State, national politics, suffrage, 1910s, Woman's Party, 1930s, League of Women Voters (local, state and national), 1934 (Box 222)
    - State, national politics, suffrage, League of Women Voters activities, 1920s-1930s (Box 223)
    - State and national politics, suffrage 1917, 1918, various other issues, 1900s-1950s (Box 224)
    - State, national politics, suffrage, 1910s-1920s, Governor's Ball, 1929, personal and family clippings (Box 225)
    - Suffrage politics, prominent men in favor of suffrage, suffrage activities in Virginia, poetry and humor relating to suffrage (Box 226)
    - Various clippings, 1910s-1930s (Box 227)
    - "Golden Flier," Newspaper Articles, 1916 (Box 227)
    - Various clippings, 1910s-1970s (Box 228)
    - Woman's Journal (complete issues, many in bad condition), 1910s (Box 229)
  - Subseries B: Ephemera, 1890s-1950s
    - A key to The Rice Hotel, Houston, Texas; a second key (Box 230)
    - button "Errand Boys, Child Labor Street Permit, Commonwealth of Virginia, #254, Department of Labor and Industry 1929, Richmond, VA." (Box 230)
    - Convention delegate pin of Delegate Cornelia Adair labeled "National League of Women Voters, 8th National Convention, Chicago, APR. 23-28, 1926" (Box 230)
    - Convention delegate pin of Adèle Clark labeled "National League of Women Voters, Fifth Annual Convention, Buffalo 1924" (Box 230)
    - Convention pin of Adèle Clark labeled Association of Governmental Labor Officials of the United States and Canada - Richmond, VA, May 1 - 4, 1923 (Box 230)
    - Two possible convention pins with the name of "Carter Glass" on them (Box 230)
    - Small jewelry box containing newspaper clippings of death notices and a lock of hair wrapped in paper and labeled "Alicia's hair for (name unable to read)" (Box 230)
    - seeds wrapped in paper (Box 230)
    - business card of Mary Johnston, Florist of Baltimore. (Box 230)
    - Sashes (six) that read "Votes for Women"; one paper sash reading "Votes for Women" (Box-folder 231:1)
    - Coin Recordio-Gram records (four) in an envelope dated 1950, sent to Mrs. Walter Watson (Box-folder 231:2)
    - Postcards (Box-folder 231:3)
    - Drawing of exercises (Box-folder 231:4)
    - Telegram from Lady Nancy Astor sent to convention of the National League of Women Voters held in Richmond, Virginia, 1925 (Box-folder 231:5)
    - Teulia Fortune Cards, undated (Box-folder 231:6)
    - The Decorator and Furnisher, January 1891 (Box-folder 231:7)
    - Calling cards of Adèle Clark, Clark and Houston Family and others (Box 232)
    - Miscellaneous fliers (Box 232)
    - Constitution of the League of Nations (Box 232)
    - 1926 calendar (Box 232)
    - Governor's certificate to Adèle Clark, commissioning her to represent "the state of Virginia at the First Annual Meeting of the American Child Health Association," 1923 (Box 232)
    - magazine photos of airplanes, reproductions of covers of New Century magazine (Box 232)
    - stationary of NLWV, VLWV, Western Union, Department of Labor and others (Box 232)
    - advertisements, invoices and bills, 1890s-1940s (Box 232)